Mytton Maury Papers
Mytton Maury Papers
1885-1904
Maury, Mytton
2.0 linear ft
Spanning 1885 to 1904, the Mytton Maury Papers comprises material collected by the American clergyman and scholar (1839-1919) primarily during the years he was revising and updating various works on geography originally edited by his cousin Matthew Fontaine Maury.
2480352
Scope and Contents of the Collection
Arranged alphabetically, the bulk of the Correspondence/subject files encompasses Dr. Maury's handwritten research notes, clippings, and correspondence relating to Maury's Manual of Geography (1892, 1894, and 1896 editions) and Maury's Physical Geography (1893 and 1894 editions) as well as notes for a proposed revision of Physical Geography of the Sea. The remainder of the collection also contains general research material and correspondence relating to a variety of geographical subjects. Copies of the published works, heavily annotated, are included in the collection.
Subject and Genre Headings
Church and clergy; Science and medicine; Maury, Mytton, Archives; Maury's Manual of Geography; Maury's Physical Geography; Physical Geography of the Sea; Physical geography; Oceanography; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Marginalia.; Authors.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Purchased: 1992
Inventory
- Correspondence / subject files
  - General correspondence, 1885-1895; undated (Box 1)
  - Family correspondence, 1892 (Box 1)
  - Archaeology (Box 1)
  - Block Island (Box 1)
  - Climate (Box 1)
  - Indians (Box 1)
  - Maury, John Draper (Box 1)
  - Maury, Matthew Fontaine (Box 1)
  - Maury's Manual of Geography, 1892 (a)
    - General notes (Box 1)
    - Chapter notes (Box 1)
      - North America (Box 1)
      - South America (Box 1)
      - Europe (Box 1)
      - Asia (Box 1)
      - Africa (Box 1)
  - Maury's Manual of Geography 1892 (b)
    - General notes (Box 2)
    - Chapter notes (Box 2)
      - North America (Box 2)
      - South America (Box 2)
      - Europe (Box 2)
      - Asia (Box 2)
      - Africa (Box 2)
      - Oceania (Box 2)
      - Recent geographical events (Box 2)
  - Maury's Manual of Geography 1894 edition
    - General notes (Box 2)
    - Chapter notes (Box 2)
      - North America (Box 2)
      - South America (Box 2)
      - Europe (Box 2)
      - Asia (Box 2)
      - Africa (Box 2)
      - Oceania (Box 2)
  - Maury's Manual of Geography 1896 edition
    - General notes (Box 3)
    - Chapter notes (Box 3)
      - Mathematical geography (Box 3)
      - Physical geography (Box 3)
      - North America (Box 3)
      - South America (Box 3)
      - Europe (Box 3)
      - Asia (Box 3)
      - Africa (Box 3)
      - Australasia (Box 2)
  - Maury's Physical Geography 1893 edition
    - General notes (Box 3)
    - Chapter notes
      - The Earth (Box 3)
      - The Land (Box 3)
      - The Water (Box 3)
      - The Atmosphere (Box 3)
      - Life (Box 3)
  - Maury's Physical Geography 1894 edition
    - General notes (Box 4)
    - Chapter notes
      - The Earth (Box 4)
      - The Land (Box 4)
      - The Water (Box 4)
      - The Atmosphere (Box 4)
      - Life (Box 4)
      - Recent Geographical Events (Box 4)
  - Missions (Box 4)
  - National Geographic Society (Box 4)
  - Nova Scotia (Box 4)
  - Physical Geography of the Sea, notes for a proposed revision (Box 4)
  - Protective tariffs (Box 4)
  - South Dakota (Box 4)
  - Texas (Box 4)
  - United States Coast and Geodetic Survey (Box 4)
  - University Publishing Company (Box 4)
  - United States Geological Survey (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 4)